The world's masters of murder pull out all the stops to destroy Agent 007!
From Russia with Love is a action, thriller,
adventure film directed by Terence Young.
Agent 007 is back in the second installment of the James Bond series, this
time battling a secret crime organization known as SPECTRE.
Russians Rosa Klebb and Kronsteen are out to snatch a decoding device known as the
Lektor, using the ravishing Tatiana to lure Bond into helping them.
Bond willingly travels to meet Tatiana in Istanbul, where he must rely on his wits to
escape with his life in a series of deadly encounters with the enemy.
James Bond, played by Sean Connery.
Tatiana 'Tanja' Romanova, played by Daniela Bianchi.
Ali Kerim Bey, played by Pedro Armendáriz.
Donald 'Red' Grant, played by Robert Shaw.
Rosa Klebb, played by Lotte Lenya.
M, played by Bernard Lee.
From Russia with Love is a 1963 spy film directed by Terence
Young and the second in the James Bond series.
It was produced by Eon Productions, starring Sean Connery
as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The picture was produced by Albert R.
Broccoli and Harry Saltzman, and written by Richard Maibaum and Johanna
Harwood, based on Ian Fleming's 1957 novel From Russia, with Love.
In the film, Bond is sent to assist in the defection of Soviet consulate clerk Tatiana
Romanova in Turkey, where SPECTRE plans to avenge Bond's killing of Dr.
Following the success of Dr.
No, United Artists greenlit a sequel and doubled the
budget available for the producers.
In addition to filming on location in Turkey, the action scenes were shot
at Pinewood Studios, Buckinghamshire, and in Scotland.
Production ran over budget and schedule, and was rushed to
finish by its scheduled October 1963 release date.
From Russia with Love was a critical and commercial success.
It took in more than $78 million in worldwide box-office receipts, far more
than its $2 million budget and more than its predecessor Dr.
No, thereby becoming a blockbuster in 1960s cinema.
In 2004, Total Film magazine named it the ninth-greatest British film of
all time; it was the only Bond film to appear on the list.
It was also the first film in the series to win a
BAFTA Award for Best Cinematography.
From Russia with Love was followed by Goldfinger in 1964.
The film explores themes of assassin, london, england,
assassination, based on novel or book, venice, italy.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.